# RODRIGO ASSAF

# 3D UX/UI Designer and Developer

Porto - Portugal

phone: +351 968 062 165 | email: rodassaf@gmail.com

#### Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rodassaf/

Hello! I am a creative technologist with a vast experience in the media & entertainment industry.

As an Autodesk technical specialist in Latin America, I won the Best Technical Specialist prize in the Americas (2016). I had the opportunity to present the official release of Autodesk 3ds Max 2017 in Las Vegas (NAB) at the Autodesk booth. Also, I was a speaker at international events such as CAPER (Argentina), Colombia 4.0, Anima Mundi (Brazil), Siggraph (USA), and Autodesk University (Mexico), presenting 3ds Max, Maya, and Shotgun.

Later, I become a customer success consultant for Autodesk achieving great business results in an M&E customer and a teacher at the University of Porto. Also, I am working as a developer in a 3D real-time studio based in London called HMX Media.

My technical specialties include Adobe Package (XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, After Effects, Premiere), 3D software (3ds Max, Maya, Mudbox, Motionbuilder, Recap), Production Management (Shotgrid), and some programming languages (Javascript - React, Threejs, and C# with Unity).

#### **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2022 (expected)

Ph.D. Candidate - Digital Media

University of Porto-FEUP

2004 - 2006

**Master of Science in Computer Science** 

Federal University of São Carlos

2000 - 2004

**Bachelor Degree in Computer Science** 

Federal University of São Carlos

### SKILLS

Language: Spanish | English | Portuguese

# AWARDS

2020: University of Porto: Pedagogical Recognition

2016: Autodesk Best Technical Specialist of America Territory

# RODRIGO ASSAF

### **EXPERIENCE**

06/2021 - today

# Front-End Developer

HMX Media - London

· Responsible for:

Integrate BOX API with Studio Infinity Platform (Java Backend)
React Developer: UI, 3D Canvas, Search bars, etc.
3D Navigation Interaction (Javascript)

04/2018 - today

### **Customer Success Consultant**

Autodesk Brazil

- · Consulting Services for Autodesk
- The account I am responsible for: the largest commercial TV network in Latin America and the second-largest of the world.
  - I developed business strategies enhancing customer satisfaction and performance establishing metrics.
  - I helped to expand products looking at opportunities via a high-value relationship with the client. Results: 2 great renewal deals closed (with growth) maintaining customer satisfaction and achieving the sales target.
- Weekly follow-ups with the stakeholders, understanding the customer's business goals and ensuring solution adoption.
  - Subject Matter Expert Consultant: Technical Content Translation to Portuguese (1h Webinar)

02/2021- today

# **Assistant Teacher**

Universidade Lusófona do Porto

- New Media Production Discipline
  - · Web Development Discipline

09/2019 - 09/2021

## **Assistant Teacher**

Faculty of Engineering | University of Porto & Post-Graduation

- WebGL and Javascript Discipline
- Game Development Discipline
  - Prototype Development

09/2011 - 12/2017

# Latin America Technical Specialist for Media & Entertainment

Autodesk Inc.

- I was the Demo Artist for the Lartin America Region. Developed content for 3ds Max, Maya, Shotgun, and Mudbox.
- · I was part of the Ranger team (pre-sales) of Shotgun.
- Created 3D visualization assets for Oil and Gas industry. My work was selected in the official showreel of Autodesk on 2016.
- I won the prize for Best Technical Sales Specialist of Americas in FY17.
- I was the technical resource for the ViveLabs Project in Colombia.
- I was responsible for strategic account planning in Latin America region.
- I did the technical sales presentation of the official release of 3ds Max 2017 at NAB Las Vegas.

#### International Technical Sales Presentations at:

- (MEX) Autodesk University Mexico Arnold Rendering: 2017
- (USA) Siggraph: (Intel, AMD and HP Booth): 2017 & 2014
- (BRA) Gramado Cinema Festival: VFX applied on Movies: 2017
- (COL) Colombia 4.0: 2016
- (BRA) Autodesk University Brazil Main Stage: 2016
- (USA) NAB Autodesk Main Stage: 2016
- (ARG) CAPER Argentina: 2015
- (USA) Siggraph: Demo @ Unity Booth and XSens Booth: 2015
- · (USA) NAB Booth Demos: 2015 | 2014 | 2013

09/2008 - 09/2011

# **3d Interactive Artist and Motion Grapher**

TV Band - Broadcast Channel

- Produce 3D Opening (Full CG) for TV
- Develop 3D Virtual Sets for VizRT
- Motion Graphics
- 3D Real Time Animation for Sport Shows

## REFERENCES

Sylvio Mode - BRA

Autodesk Country Director T: +55 11 94857 4991 E: sylvio.mode@autodesk.com Wagner Franchin - PT

Oracle Developer
T: +351 913 138 362
E: wagner.franchin@oracle.com

# RODRIGO ASSAF

## **PUBLISHED ARTICLES**

#### 2020

Assaf, R., & Rodrigues, R. (2020). Immersive challenges of interacting and publishing 3D content on the Web. In **Digicom - International Conference on Design & Digital Communication**. Barcelos, Portugal: IPCA Procedings.

Assaf, R., Kunz, S., & Teixeira, L. (2020). The Presence of the Uncanny Valley Between Animation and Cinema: A Communication Approach. In C. Soares & E. Simão (Eds.), **Multidisciplinary Perspectives on New Media Art** (1st ed., p. 300). Hershey, PA: IGI Global.

#### 2019

Assaf, R., & Rodrigues, R. (2019). The feeling of presence: An immersive perspective. In **Artech-International Conference on Digital and Interactive Arts** (p. 6). Braga, Portugal: ACM, New York.

Silva, M., Assaf, R., Pollini, D., Morais, D., & Teixeira, L. (2019). The Apprentice Gaze - AR Experience on Serralves Museum. In Artech - International Conference on Digital and Interactive Arts (p. 5). Braga, Portugal: ACM, New York.